Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. So, we are currently positioned
squarely in the inter war period in
American history. So, here's a good
question to ask after World War I.
Should America lead globally or stay out
of foreign conflicts? If you want to
know the answer to this question, it is
mostly to stay out of everything,
meaning to be isolationist. However,
there were quite a few things that
happened that went against this
ideology. The first of this is two
things. The DAW plan was made because
Germany could not pay for its
reparations and Europe was struggling as
a result. So the plan was to loan
Germany money which after Germany paid
their reparations allowed Britain and
France to pay off their US war debts.
Then later the Kellogg brand pact was
passed in which most countries pledged
to not solve world problems with war.
And if you can't tell both of these
things did not work. The DAS plan failed
because of the Great Depression and the
Kellogg Brand Pact failed because there
was no way it could be enforced. It's
also important to note that the US
continued intervention and continued
presence in Latin America and the
Caribbean such as in Haiti and
Nicaragua. But now we see something else
rise in Europe and that is a very famous
mustache man with an ideology of fascism
growing very strong. The US sensed war
might come and pass a series of
neutrality acts which didn't really
work. And over in Europe, our good
friend Hitler is conquering land and the
horrible method of appeasement isn't
alleviating it. Once FDR realizes these
Axis powers are dangerous, he slowly
starts moving away from isolationism.
And then out of nowhere, bam, the naval
base Pearl Harbor is bombed by the Axis
power Japan and America officially
enters World War II. On the screen now
are AP style questions for this topic.
Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.